Rob Houck

WEB DEVELOPER

Details

Cleveland, OH 4408293737 rbhouck32@gmail.com

Links

Github

LinkedIn

Skills

HTML5

CSS3

jQuery

JavaScript

Git

Bootstrap

Django

Python

React

WCAG Compliance

Agile

Postgre SQL

Continuous Integration

Deployment

Knex

Express.js

Node.js

MySQL

RESTful API

SQL

Database Management

Data Structures

Hobbies

Camping, Hiking, Fishing, Working on my car

Profile

Experienced Software Developer with a passion for Front End Web Development. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill set. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including JavaScript, J query HTML, CSS, Django, and React with a deep understanding of WCAG compliance and web accessibility.

Employment History

Front End Application Developer, Qwickly Inc, Cleveland OH

OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT

HTML5 | CSS3 | Figma | jQuery | Django | Python | Bootstrap

Qwickly Design System (October 2021 - Present)

 Collaborated with UI/UX designer to implement design system into a reusable component library for company developers to provide a more uniform look and feel across all products and increase productivity among developers.

Course Tools Redesign (March 2022 - June 2022)

- Reviewed existing legacy code base and planned collaboratively with back-end developer to assess technical debt and plan for future feature development.
- Refactored and organized existing JavaScript code base to asynchronous components where applicable in order to improve application performance and enhance responsiveness.
- Rebuilt UI using design files as a reference, this included providing conditional rendering of views for the user, form validation, dynamic data-driven rendering of reusable components, messaging, error handling, accessibility auditing, and responsiveness.

Accessibility Auditing (February 2022 - Present)

 Tasked with reviewing legacy code within the applications and edited code if needed to ensure that code meets WCAG Accessibility guidelines.

Qwickly Dashboard Redesign (October 2022 - November 2022)

- Tasked with restructuring the legacy code base of the existing internal dashboard into the new design and ensuring that previous functionality is maintained.
- Built data-driven components that could be utilized within the redesign that provide clients with a more tailored customized experience.

Qwickly Jot Tool (April 2023 - Present)

Refactored front-end framework using Qwickly Design System to give product
a better overall UX and a more cohesive feel among Qwickly product set.
This included the creation of asynchronously loaded components using Django
templating language for more of a single-page application feel for the user.

Education

Full-stack Web Development, Lambda School, Remote

OCTOBER 2019 - APRIL 2021

16-month long Intensive computer science and software engineering training program
focused on software engineering and full-stack web development using an immersive
hands-on approach